Joseph M Hurd

13 McMichael Ct. • Somerdale, NJ 08083 • 609-706-5153 josephmartinhurd@gmail.com

Dear Hiring Committee,

I am a Software Developer and Software Engineering student based in the Greater Philadelphia region and I am seeking to become a member of a professional software development team. I am passionate about transforming mobile devices into tools for education, entertainment, and convenience, and I have 2-3 years of experience developing cross-platform mobile applications for iOS and Android devices.

As a student, my primary focus is on developing cross-platform mobile and desktop applications using C#, .NET, Xamarin, and Visual Studio. However, I have also studied and worked with Object Oriented Programming languages such as Java, Python, and C++, Web Development languages such as HTML and CSS, Relational Database Management languages and systems such as SQL, PostgreSQL, and MySQL, and notable concepts and techniques such as Data Structures and Algorithms, Agile, and Full Stack Development. I am currently more than 75% completed with my degree program and I am expecting to graduate by December of 2023 with a B.S. in Software Engineering. I have obtained the following certifications: CompTIA A+, CompTIA Project+, ITIL IT Service Management, and AWS Cloud Practitioner.

As an independent Mobile Application Developer, my primary workflow includes but is not limited to C#, JSON, Unity, Visual Studio, Xcode, Android Studio, and Figma. My mobile applications currently serve specific userbases in the respective fields of education, entertainment, and convenience. While my apps are dedicated towards specific use cases in niche communities, they have been installed by thousands of users in over 40 countries around the world. I have converted 37% of my Apple product page viewers into users, and each app that I have published holds a 5-star rating on the iOS App Store. If you would like to view my work, you can find my live portfolio at joethehurd.io, which I am hosting on GitHub Pages with static HTML files that I developed using WordPress on my local PHP server.

I am confident that my versatility and commitment towards growth enable me to make key contributions to a professional development team with various needs. If you believe that my background can serve as a unique and beneficial force on your team, I would love for the opportunity to discuss how I can meaningfully help achieve your goals and objectives.

All of my best,

Joseph Hurd

Joseph M Hurd

13 McMichael Ct. • Somerdale, NJ 08083 • 609-706-5153 josephmartinhurd@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering		
Rowan University, Glassboro, NJ	2017 - 2020	
Bachelor of Arts, History	GPA: 3.7	
Bachelor of Arts, Secondary Education	GPA: 3.9	
President's List, Magna Cum Laude Honors		
Camden County College, Blackwood, NJ	2012 - 2017	
Associate in Science, Secondary/Elementary Education	GPA: 3.0	

RELATED SKILLS & EXPERIENCE

•	Object-Oriented Programming	using C#, C++, Java, Python, Visual Studio
•	Data Management	using JSON, PHP, SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL
•	Mobile Development	using Unity, Xamarin, Xcode, Android Studio
•	Web Development	using HTML, CSS, WordPress, GitHub Pages
•	UI/UX Design	using Figma, Inkscape, AutoCAD, Adobe XD
•	Asset/Media Production	using Blender, REAPER, DaVinci, GIMP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mobile Application Developer, Somerdale, NJ

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT

2021 - Present

2022 - Present

Cross-Platform Mobile Development

- Independently develop and publish mobile applications to the Google Play Console and iOS App Store.
- Routinely perform debugging and version control, consistently optimize and upload new build packages, and utilize user data to improve application functionality and performance.
- Design all UI/UX elements, model all application assets, and create all music, sounds, and themes.
- Implement monetization through in-app purchases and 3rd party advertisements.
- Integrate 3rd party APIs to collect user metrics, manage cloud data, launch haptics, and build community leaderboards containing challenges, high scores, and user statistics.
- Globally distribute mobile applications to thousands of users in more than 40 countries, convert 37% of product page viewers into users, and maintain 5-star ratings for all distributed applications.

Joseph M Hurd

13 McMichael Ct. ● Somerdale, NJ 08083 ● 609-706-5153 josephmartinhurd@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE cont.

Woodbury Junior-Senior High School, Woodbury, NJ

2020 - 2021

Social Studies Teacher of Alternative Education, Certified 6-12

- Curated and administered the Humanities curriculum for 6th through 12th grade Alternative Education students, while leading elective courses in Art Appreciation, Fundamental Math, and Business and Technology.
- Attentively participated in professional development conferences and reliably collaborated with staff and colleagues to coordinate a comprehensive effort to best meet the needs of all students.
- Served as a personal learning advocate and actively communicated with students and guardians to maintain and improve student attendance, engagement, and performance.

Freelance Editor, Somerdale, NJ

2017 - 2020

Editor, Mentor

- Assisted undergraduate and graduate students with the drafting, refining, and finalizing of their research papers.
- Provided valuable insights regarding students' gathering, analyzing, and interpreting of data, and guided students' research methodologies and communication techniques.

Sylvestro Consulting, Glassboro, NJ

2014 - 2017

Lead Draftsman

- Specialized in the conceptualization of mechanical, electrical, and plumbing design for consumer-based architecture projects.
- Designed, printed, and delivered engineering-consultant drawings while also maintaining positive client relations in a competitive and professional field.
- Directed a team of draftsmen, taught new employees how to conceptualize within computer-aided drafting software, and designated workloads to optimize efficiency, performance, and business outcomes.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner

CompTIA Project+

issued by Amazon Web Services, 2023

issued by CompTIA, 2023

issued by CompTIA, 2022

sucd by *comp1111*, **2022**

issued by Axelos, 2022

• CompTIA A+

• ITIL IT Service Management

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Hobbies/Interests: Drumming, Kayaking, Snowboarding, Mountain Biking, Music

Production, Game Development, Sociology, and the Oxford Comma

Member: Phi Alpha Theta National History Honor Society, Psi Iota Chapter

References available upon request.